rachaelray.com 2018-12-07

# Privacy Policy - Rachael Ray

Rachael Ray Digital LLC (“RRD”) is committed to providing information and activities relating to Rachael Ray on the rachaelray.com website (the “Site”). Our content includes information about Rachael Ray and her various endeavors, products, recipes, photos, videos, and interactivity with our users and also provides links to other sites Rachael Ray may or may not be affiliated with. This website is only intended for use by U.S. residents.

RRD respects privacy rights, and is committed to safeguarding the personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) entrusted to us by our clients and visitors to our Site. RRD has implemented this Privacy Policy to govern the use of Personal Information that we collect through the Site, including Personal Information you send to us. **This Privacy Policy does not govern Personal Information collected from any other source or in any other manner.** This Privacy Policy is intended to provide you with information as to: (i) the type of information that is collected, (ii) how the collected information is used and with whom it is shared; (iii) how we intend to protect the information; and (iv) how you can access such information and have it modified and/or removed.

This Privacy Policy may be changed from time to time. We will post changes to the Site, and we reserve the right to make changes without prior individual notice. Such changes are effective upon posting. Please review this Privacy Policy often so that you will remain abreast of RRD’s current policies, including its policies concerning the gathering and use of information that may be collected on our Site. You are responsible for making sure you are aware of the provisions of RRD’s most current Privacy Policy. You can tell when the Privacy Policy was last modified by checking the “updated” date.

The Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference in and made a part of our Terms and Conditions of Use of the Site, and explains how users’ information and data is collected and used.

  * Your California Privacy Rights
  * Collection and Use of Information
  * Personal Information
  * Financial Information
  * IP Address
  * Other Information
  * Your Consent
  * Use of Your Personal Information

  *     * Opting In and Opting Out of Electronic Communications
    * Do Not Track Signals
    * Use of Your Personal Information within RRD
    * Use of Your Personal Information by Our Service Providers
    * If RRD changes ownership
    * Lawful access, legal action and investigations.

  * Use of Cookies, Google Analytics
  * Disclosure of Information to Non-Affiliated Third Parties
  * Retention of Personal Information
  * Your Privacy Choices – Limiting Information Sharing/Accessing Your Information
  * Protection and Security of Information
  * Use of the Site by Children
  * Links to Other Websites
  * Governing Law
  * Contact Us

 **California Privacy Rights**

Under California law, California residents who have provided personal information to a company may have the right to request a list of all third parties to whom that company had disclosed such information for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, along with a list of the categories of personal information that had been so disclosed. However, if a company adopts and discloses a privacy policy that provides the ability to opt-out of such disclosures to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes, then the company is not required to maintain and provide such lists, and instead may provide you with information on how to exercise your right to prevent disclosure of your personal information. Because the privacy policy as disclosed on this Site provides you with an opportunity to opt-out of disclosures by us of your Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes, we do not have to provide you with such lists. If you are a California resident who would like information on how to exercise your rights concerning third party disclosures, you may send an email [privacy@rachaelray.com](mailto:privacy@rachaelray.com). **Attn: California Privacy Rights Administrator**

 **Collection and Use of Information**

 _Personal Information_

Personal Information is information that uniquely identifies you, such as your name, address, email address and telephone number. At times, RRD may collect your Personal Information. For example, we collect your Personal Information if you register for portions of the Site that may require registration, enter a sweepstakes or contest, complete a survey, subscribe to our newsletters, or send us an email, and provide us with your name, address, telephone number and/or email address. We may also collect your Personal Information if you post, display and or publish materials on the Site or if users send us stories, recipes, photos and/or other materials (“User Content”), and we post these materials on our Site. We also may display a child’s photo or artwork, or photos that show images of any children, but we will only show a child’s first name and age. We will not show any last names or addresses, including email or postal. We will not use material without the consent of the user. We will not return any User Content, including but not limited to materials, such as photographs, once they have been sent to us.

Any information collected about you from the Site may be associated with other information that RRD has collected about you. REMEMBER to exercise discretion and caution with respect to User Content that you provide to us and/or post on the Site. Personal Information that you provide to us will not be held confidentially, and it may be publicly viewable. With respect to all communications you make to or through the Site, including but not limited to feedback, questions, comments, suggestions and the like: (i) you shall have no right to confidentiality in your communications and RRD shall have no obligation to protect your communications from disclosure; (ii) RRD shall be free to reproduce, use, publish, display, disclose and distribute your communications to others without limitation, in any way now known or hereafter devised; and (iii) RRD shall be free to use any ideas, concepts, know-how, information, data content or techniques contained in your communications for any purpose whatsoever, including but not limited to, the development, production and marketing of products and services that incorporate such information, without any compensation to you.

 _Financial Information_

This Site does not collect your financial information. However, when you click to shop Rachael’s products on the Site, you will be redirected to a website hosted by Meredith (<https://www.rachaelray.com/shop/> or the “Shop”). No purchases or sales are made on this site, but rather, are conducted via the websites of the retailers who advertise their inventory there. Information collected on the Shop is not governed by the Privacy Policy and/or Terms and Conditions of this Site. You should read the Privacy Policy and any Terms and Conditions on the Shop to understand the ways in which your Personal Information is stored and/or protected. Similarly, you may subscribe to newsletters or magazines, or visit other websites that are related to or affiliated with this Site and which may collect your financial information. Such websites are not governed by the Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions of this Site. You are encouraged to review the policies and terms of these other websites to understand how your Personal Information, including your financial information, is collected and maintained by such websites.

 _IP Address_

An IP (Internet Protocol) address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer by your internet service provider when you log on. RRD anonymizes the collection of IP addresses via Google Analytics (see below for more), which you can read more about here: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2763052?hl=en>. Some IP address information is collected, which may help us identify information including, but not limited to, geographic trends and/or usage information. However, full IP addresses identifying individuals are not collected.

 _Other Information_

When you access the Site, RRD will automatically receive some information about your use of the service. The type of information that is automatically collected by RRD includes, but is not limited to, such things as the date and time of access of the Site, the anonymized Internet protocol (IP) address of the computer that you are using, the domain and host from which you access the Internet, your browser software and operating system, the referring website address, and the specific activities you are engaged in while visiting the Site. This aggregate tracking information is used to help RRD improve and enhance the website experience for all of its visitors.

 _Your Consent_

We only collect, use and/or disclose your Personal Information with your consent. We will ask for your affirmative consent when we collect your Personal Information, such as when we ask for your e-mail address or for your consent to our use of cookies, as explained below. Your consent may also be given for a particular purpose. For example, when you submit your Personal Information to us by emailing us, you are consenting to the collection, handling, use and disclosure of your Personal Information for the purposes of responding to you.

 _Use of Your Personal Information_

We use your Personal Information for the purposes for which it is submitted, such as to reply to your emails and inquiries, and to allow you to participate in promotions, such as contests. Your Personal Information may also be used in the following ways:

  * to deliver materials, information and services to you,
  * to give you notice of and/or resolve any problems that may arise in connection with our services,
  * to better understand the needs and interests of our customers,
  * to analyze the success of our products and services and Site,
  * to manage the Site’s interactive functionality,
  * to help RRD improve and enhance the Site experience for all of its visitors, and customize the content on our Site,
  * for compliance with RRD’s legal and regulatory obligations,
  * as otherwise reasonably required to provide customer services and maintain the Site,
  * to investigate potential breaches of the Terms and Conditions of the Site,
  * to investigate potentially unlawful activity,
  * for any other purpose outlined in this Privacy Policy and/or the Terms and Conditions of which this Privacy Policy is a part, and
  * as permitted by law.

We may, under certain circumstances, also use your Personal Information to contact you via direct postal mail and/or electronically to the extent such activity is permitted by law, and, with your consent, regarding your relationship with RRD. This information may also be used to help RRD and its commercial partners deliver targeted advertisements, promotions and other initiatives to you.

Opting in and opting out of electronic communications. At certain points where Personal Information is collected on our Site, there may be a box to indicate that you wish to receive certain information or communications from RRD. You may also opt out of receiving electronic communications, such as emails from RRD, at any time, using the Unsubscribe links provided in those emails. In all of our electronic communications, you will be given the opportunity to opt out of receiving future communications. You may also opt-out or change your preferences by sending an email to info@rachaelray.com.

 _Do Not Track Signals_

Certain web browsers provide users with an option by which you may have your browser send a “Do Not Track” signal to the website that you are visiting, advising the recipient website that you do not want to have your online activity tracked. However, the way browsers communicate such “Do Not Track” signals is not yet uniform and accordingly, our Site does not take any action in response to such signals. In the event a final standard is developed and accepted, we may reassess how we should respond to such signals.

 _Use of Your Personal Information Within RRD_

In order to provide you with efficient and reliable services and to improve product and service options available to you, RRD may share your Personal Information with our affiliated entities, in which case your personal information will be collected, used, disclosed, managed and stored in accordance with this policy as set forth herein. Our affiliates are companies controlled or owned by us, or companies that control us, or are under common control with us. The Site is intended for users in the United States and its territories and possessions. If you use the Site from any country outside the United States, the various communications will necessarily result in the transfer of information across international boundaries, and by visiting the Site, you consent to these transfers as required or permitted by applicable law.

 _Use of Your Personal Information by Our Service Providers_

From time to time, we may hire third parties to assist us with certain functions and services, such as data processing, computer software and website maintenance and development, promotional and marketing services, customer service, professional, legal or accounting services and/or business and sales analysis. RRD may share your Personal Information, without restriction (and regardless of whether you have chosen to limit our sharing of your Personal Information as collected on the Site), with such companies that we hire to perform services for us. In such situations, RRD requires that these companies agree to maintain the confidentiality of your Personal Information and to comply with the safeguards described in this Privacy Policy. These companies have access to the Personal Information needed to perform their functions but are not permitted to share or use such information for any other purposes. Furthermore, in compliance with privacy laws, we also provide our opt-out lists to non-affiliated third party companies so that communications sent by those companies on RRD’s behalf do not get sent to addresses appearing on our opt-out lists.

 _If RRD Changes Ownership_

We may also share your Personal Information as required to allow for a change in ownership of RRD and/or any of RRD’s affiliated entities and/or of any business(es) to which the Site relates, and the related transfer of user information to the new owner. In the event of any such change of ownership, your Personal Information will continue to be protected by the terms of this Privacy Policy unless and until you are notified of a change.

 _Lawful Access, Legal Action and Investigations_

Your Personal Information may be disclosed to non-affiliated third parties as either permitted by, or to comply with, applicable laws and regulations. Your Personal Information may be transmitted through and stored on servers outside your home country, and may be accessed by authorities in those jurisdictions. We may disclose Personal Information if we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected illegal activities or fraud, situations involving the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms and Conditions, or otherwise in accordance with applicable law. For example, RRD may disclose your Personal Information to comply with investigations by regulatory authorities or enforcement agencies in the United States of America or elsewhere, or to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud. Furthermore, RRD may disclose your Personal Information if it has a reasonable good faith basis to believe that it is required to do so by law, compelled by court order or legal process, or is reasonably necessary and/or appropriate to: (i) protect the rights, property and/or safety of RRD or any other person or entity; or (ii) prevent or take action concerning any alleged: (a) illegal activity or (b) breach of the Terms and Conditions or Privacy Policy of the Site.

 _Use of Cookies, Google Analytics_

The Site makes use of “cookies” – small data files which we may send to your computer on the basis of the information that we have collected about your visit. They contain information allowing us to recognize when you are visiting the Site and to keep track of your preferences. Through the use of a cookie, we also may automatically collect information about your online activity on our Site, such as the web pages you visit, the links you click, and the searches you conduct on our site. Cookies are stored in your computer’s browser or on your hard disk and can then be retrieved by the website.

We may also use third-party advertising companies to target and show you advertisements when you visit the Site. On occasion, RRD may permit third-party advertisers and ad networks to place their own cookies on our Site to track visitors’ activities on the Site. This enables such companies to recognize visitors so that when those visitors visit a third-party website, advertising can be delivered that is tailored to their individual interests (whether for RRD products or for the products or services of others), based on what has been learned from the visitors’ activity on RRD’s Site. This practice is called “interest-based advertising,” and the practices of these third-parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

RRD offers you choices about the collection of information on our Site. RRD adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. If you decide you do not want to receive personalized ads from third-party advertisers and ad networks please visit [www.AboutAds.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choice), where you can learn more about opting out from receiving interest-based advertising.

If you want to delete any cookies that were already sent to your computer or personal device, please refer to your web browser’s “Help” facility. In addition, most web browsers can be set to prevent you from receiving new cookies, notify you before accepting cookies or disable cookies altogether. Details about this can normally be found in the “Help” facility provided with your browser. Please note that if you disable cookies you may not be able to take advantage of some of the Site’s interactive functionality.

The Site uses Google Analytics, a web analytics tools that helps website owners understand how visitors engage with their website. We can view a variety of reports about how visitors interact with our Site so we can improve it. Google Analytics collects information anonymously, and uses cookies, and anonymized IP addresses, and reports website trends without identifying individual visitors. For more information related to Google Analytics, click here: http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html. You can opt-out of Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-On. For information about and to install Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on, click here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

 _Disclosure of Information to Non-Affiliated Third Parties_

RRD does not sell or market the Personal Information collected on the Site to non-affiliated third parties for their marketing purposes without your express consent. Other aggregated and/or anonymous information may be disclosed without your consent. RRD may disclose aggregated statistics about visitors to its Site, along with anonymous information concerning individual visitors of its Site. We may combine anonymous information and/or aggregate information we collect with additional anonymous information collected from other sources. We may share anonymous information (including aggregate information) we collect regarding our users with third parties (such as advisors, promotional sponsors, and investors) for various business purposes including conducting general business analysis, and developing website content and services.

 _Retention of Personal Information_

Personal Information is retained to deliver our services, to otherwise fulfill identified or apparent purposes, and for record-keeping. At some point RRD may elect to destroy, erase or anonymize your Personal Information. Once anonymized, RRD undertakes not to re-identify the information.

Information posted on the Site may continue to be displayed on this Site, or on any successor website for as long as the Site or any successor Site is available, and may be archived by third party Sites. You may request access to your Personal Information in order for it to be updated or removed by writing to info@rachaelray.com. To the extent permitted by applicable law, we reserve the right to refuse requests for the removal of Personal Information from the Site.

 _Your Privacy Choices – Limiting Information Sharing/Accessing Your Information_

You may have the right to request access to the Personal Information that we hold about you, which includes the right to amend or correct that information, as appropriate, and to receive an account of how it has been used and a list of the organizations to whom it has been disclosed. In some circumstances, you may have the right to object to RRD’s use of that Personal Information. You may request access and update your Personal Information by writing to [info@rachaelray.com](mailto:info@rachaelray.com).

To protect the confidentiality of your information and respect your wishes for how it is used, RRD offers “opt out” alternatives. Specifically, you may instruct us not to share Personal Information about you with our affiliated entities. As noted above, you may also opt-out of receiving electronic communications from us at any time. You may make your privacy choice at any time and it will remain in effect until you change it.

If you would like to check, change, or confirm your privacy choices please contact us at: [privacy@rachaelray.com](mailto:privacy@rachaelray.com).

 _Protection and Security of Information_

RRD maintains reasonable standards of confidentiality and security for the Site and the Personal Information collected from the Site. Physical, technical, electronic and managerial procedures have been employed to safeguard the security and integrity of Personal Information collected through the Site. The Personal Information you provide is secured using industry standard security technology. RRD also restricts its own employees’ access to Personal Information. However, it is possible that someone may intercept or access communications, transmissions and/or Personal Information.

In the event that RRD determines that there has been a security breach that results in the unauthorized disclosure of Personal Information to a third party, RRD will promptly notify consumers whose Personal Information it reasonably believes has been compromised by posting information on the Site and, if email contact is possible, then also by sending an email notification with respect to the situation.

You acknowledge that the security of online transactions you conduct using the Site cannot be guaranteed. To the fullest extent permitted at law, RRD shall not accept responsibility for misuse or loss of, or unauthorized access to, your Personal Information.

 _Use of the Site by Children_

You must be 18 years of age to use the Site. RRD does not knowingly collect or maintain information from children under the age of 13, and no part of the Site is designed with the intention of attracting such children.

 _Links to Other Websites and Services_

The RRD Site may contain links to other websites that are not controlled and/or maintained by RRD. Please be aware that these other Site may have different privacy policies which may subject you to different privacy practices. Please review the privacy policies of such other websites for information concerning what information is collected on such websites and how it is used. RRD is not responsible for the contents or privacy practices of any linked site or any link on a linked site.

Our Site also includes social media features, such as Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and Pinterest. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the feature, which we encourage you to review.

 _Governing Law_

This Privacy Policy shall be governed by the laws of the State of New York of the United States of America, without regard to its conflict of law provisions. [Please click here](http://www.rachaelray.com/terms-conditions/) to review the terms relating to Disputes and Governing Law for the Site.

 _Contact Us_

If you have any questions or complaints concerning this Privacy Policy or our handling of your Personal Information (other than with respect to California Privacy Rights) you may contact us at [info@rachaelray.com](mailto:info@rachaelray.com).

If you have any questions concerning California Privacy Rights you may contact us at [info@rachaelray.com](mailto:info@rachaelray.com) or write to us at:

RRD  
Attn: California Privacy Rights Administrator  
900 Broadway, Suite 1001  
New York, NY 10003
